OMAR TANTAWY

Software Engineer

Email: Omar.tantawee@gmail.com
Address: Zahraa Naser city, Cairo, Egypt
Phone: 0100 3863683
LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/omarTantawe

OBJECTIVE

Software engineer with more than 1 year experience chasing a career that increases my knowledge in development, testing and maintaining. Seeking to use proven skills in web applications development using .NET MVC and open for learning any new technologies & opportunities.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer, Raya Holding, Integration department, 6^{th} October, Egypt 10/2020 – present

- Developing banking solution (web-based application).
- Developing services and windows application installed on ATMs.
- Testing and debuging.
- Maintaining and supporting legacy projects.
- Configuring servers for applications deployment.

Software Engineer, TEA Serv, Cairo, Egypt

2/2020 - 6/2020

• Developing and testing windows forms application for Engineering Authority of the Egyptian Armed Forces.

Web Developer (Trainee), TEA Computers, Cairo, Egypt 6/2019 – 9/2019

• Learning and applying web-based applications using .NET MVC.

EDUCATION

Computer and Information Science, Ain Shams university, Cairo, Egypt

2016 - 2020

Accumulative grade: Good.

Graduation project grade: Excellent.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

.NET: Strong knowledge in .NET MVC, .NET Windows service, .NET Windows Forms and .NET WCF

• .NET Core: .NET MVC

• Web development: RESTful APIs

Database: Database management using SQL & PL/SQL

• Concepts: OOP & Problem solving

Programming Languages: C# – Dart - C++
 Scripting Languages: JavaScript – Python
 Markup language: HTML – CSS - Razor
 Servers: Microsoft windows server

• **Hosting:** Microsoft IIS (Internet Information Services).

• **Version Control:** Git

PROJECTS

- *ATM Portal*: web-based application developed with ASP.NET MVC to manage and control various functions on ATMs and generate reports using Crystal reports and RDLC.
- *ATM Surveillance*: .NET Service responsible for recording each transaction from all cameras connected using multi-threading and event listener, also encrypts each video after it's recorded. The listener is responsible for sending required videos upon request from the ATM portal.
- *Smart Wallet*: WCF project works as a gateway between the ATMs and the required service provider; handles requests coming from ATMs and sends the required data to the required service provider and vice versa to perform certain Wallet functions on ATMs. (using SOAP)
- *Licensing Automation*: .NET windows forms application designed for Engineering Authority of the Armed Forces to automate the land licensing process.
- ACCD: (Graduation Project) Automatic Car Crash Detection system; cross-platform mobile
 application developed with Flutter and a web-based application developed with .NET MVC. The
 mobile application automatically detects if the user is involved in a car accident using the builtin mobile sensors and notify a pre-registered user with a notification and a SMS message, also
 contains several related functionalities. The web-based application was made mainly for reports
 and accidents visualization on maps.

INTERPERSONAL SKILLS

- Object-oriented thinking and business-focused.
- Eager to learn, self-learner and open for new technologies/methods.
- Excellent communication and presentation skills.
- Ability to deal with clients and extract business and functional requirements.
- English: Excellent